<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Luke Tomes</title>
    <link>http://www.example.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Luke Tomes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.example.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Campaign Narrative: Nebraska&#39;s Second Congressional District</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/posts/2022-12-07-nebraska-campaign-narrative/nebraska-campaign-narrative/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/posts/2022-12-07-nebraska-campaign-narrative/nebraska-campaign-narrative/</guid>
      <description>This website has been dedicated entirely toward learning how to predict political elections. For the first seven blog posts, I explored potential variables that can influence my prediction for how candidates will fare in elections, and I refined those variables to maximize their predictive power. Then, I went on to predict the Fall 2022 midterm elections, including forecasting in three separate cases:
Democratic Party’s National Vote Share Democratic Party’s National Seat Share Democratic Party Candidate’s Vote Share in a Nebraska’s Second Congressional District After my initial analysis, prior to my prediction, I discovered seven useful variables (with more thorough descriptions here) that provided me a fairly accurate, predictive forecast:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-Election Reflection</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/posts/2022-11-22-post-election-reflection/post-election-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/posts/2022-11-22-post-election-reflection/post-election-reflection/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago, I released my predictions for the Fall 2022 midterm elections. Over the course of this fall season, I had explored potential variables that can influence my prediction for how candidates will fare in elections, and I refined those variables to maximize their predictive power. In summary, my model was not the most accurate on many fronts, providing me an opportunity to learn where I had went wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2022 Midterm Elections Forecast</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/posts/election_forecast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/posts/election_forecast/</guid>
      <description>In this blog, I have produced my final prediction for the upcoming Fall 2022 Midterm Elections. After exploring potential variables that can influence my predictions for how Democrats will fare and refining those variables, I have finalized my current models for the national-level prediction and the district-level predictions. First, I will explain how my models work, and I will justify why I included the variables that have been inputted. Next, I will interpret how my models perform and put them through a test to validate their effectiveness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fortifying My Model</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/posts/fortified-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/posts/fortified-model/</guid>
      <description>This week’s blog post is more geared toward housekeeping and fortifying my model. My reasoning for this is because my forecast has tumbled downhill in the past three weeks. When I began to incorporate more district-specific variables into my district forecast, I ran into the issue of working with data limited in scope (like expert predictions, turnout data, and advertising numbers).
The reality in which my model was operating contained few observations per district (oftentimes 2-3 observations), which is not ideal when searching for trends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Turnout Game</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/posts/turnout/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/posts/turnout/</guid>
      <description>Examining voting turnout is the theme for this week’s blog, and previous turnout data will be utilized in predicting elections. At first glance, turnout is not an obvious predicting variable when it comes to forecasting elections. After all, one might believe increased turnout in a district, for example, just means that there will be the same vote share, and a proportional increase in each party’s total vote count. However, it could be an important factor in toss-up districts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Media Advertising Matter?</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/posts/media-advertising/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/posts/media-advertising/</guid>
      <description>In this blog, I will seek to highlight how advertising in the airwaves can be used in predicting elections. To start, I will explore the relationships between the number of ads run in a district by each candidate and then use the 2018 advertising data as a stand-in, because I currently do not have the data from the current 2022 cycle, for my 2022 midterm elections prediction.
How Ad Money is Distirbuted Professor Ryan D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incumbency Advantage</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/posts/2022-10-03-incumbency-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/posts/2022-10-03-incumbency-advantage/</guid>
      <description>In this blog, I will seek to highlight how incumbency and expert ratings can be used in predicting elections. To start, I will compare how expert predictions compare to the actual election results in 2018, and then extrapolate the variable of expert ratings into my election modeling forecast
Seatshare from 2018 Congressional Elections by Party and Incumbency Below, I have mapped the actual result of the 2018 congresisonal midterms in terms of seat share attained by each party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incorporating Polling into a Forecast</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/posts/polling-forecasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/posts/polling-forecasts/</guid>
      <description>Why Polling Matters Forecasting elections has been a pastime of politically savvy Americans ever since one can remember. After all, it’s a challenge that no one has yet to master this practice on a consistent, election-to-election basis — there are simply too many changing variables (in terms of presence and weighting) each cycle.
Professional polls attempt to conquer this task by going directly to the voters, asking how they anticipate voting in the next election.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Economic Indicators to Predict Elections</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/posts/economic-indicators/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/posts/economic-indicators/</guid>
      <description>President Bill Clinton’s 1992 campaign is famous for coining the phrase, “It’s the Economy, Stupid!” in reference to the importance of the economy when it comes to elections. This brings the question of which economic indicators can predict the election more accurately. In this blog, I will explore the relationships between key economic variables and voting data in order to see which display greater correlations.
How Inflation Affects the Incumbent Party in the House of Representatives Over the course of the previous year, Americans have been strained by rocketing inflation that reached an annualized rate of 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Previous Electoral Indicators: House Elections Data</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/posts/house-elections-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/posts/house-elections-data/</guid>
      <description>This blog is part of a series of articles meant to progressively understand how election data can be used to predict future outcomes. I will add to this site on a weekly basis under the direction of Professor Ryan D. Enos. In the run-up to the midterm elections on November 8, 2022, I will draw on all I have learned regarding what best forecasts election results, and I will predict the outcome of the NE-02 U.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
